Welcome to Business Central Launch
Edition 2026
Wave 2 and welcome to Expense Agent
Project Handling Session.
So, we will try to explain you what is
new in Expense Agent related with a
project postings and project operations.
So, in general, one small improvement,
but really important. If you remember in
first release, we already enabled to use
projects into expense reports. So, once
when you post expense report, we will
get created
project ledger entries as well. But now,
we did much more because you asked you
sent a feedback that you wanted to use
projects in a web app. So, we enabled
this option. So, what you need to do in
a setup guide, you needed to
enable project tracking. But when you
enable project tracking, you have two
options. You can choose all projects or
assigned projects. By all projects means
you will see all your users will see all
projects in a web app. But in a case
that you want only specific projects,
you need to choose assigned projects.
Why you need it? Because it can happen
that you have hundreds of projects and
it will not be easy to find the right
one you want to use in a web app. Or on
other side, it can be top secret some of
projects, so you want to show to your
users only projects where they are
assigned for. So, this is a first place
in a setup you need to decide if you
want to enable if this is assigned or
all projects. If you do not enable, you
will not see project option in your web
app at all.
So, once when you do it, we need to
if you want to show, you we need to have
some additional configuration how to
configure assignments.
Because all projects, you will see all,
but by assigned, what does it mean?
You You can go to projects. So, now this
is new functionality of project card and
you will find assigned resources.
In assigned resources, you can select
resources you want to uh assign to these
projects and all of these resources will
see this project in the web app.
You can do it per project. So, if you do
it for projects,
uh these users will see
uh all projects and all tasks related to
these projects. But, if you want to
assign uh users only to specific tasks,
you can go to lines and choose project
task lines and resources
to the specific task and then
your users can choose only task where
they are assigned.
To make it,
we have two prerequisites and uh what
does it mean?
First, you need to create a resource for
your uh employees. They need to have
created resource. A second, you need to
assign the source to employee in
employee card. You can see on a page
where you need to do it, administration.
You just need to select resource number
on employee card and system will
recognize easily when you're working
with expense management. So, let's
switch to the expense agent to show you
how it works in the practice.
So, before I start, I first want to show
what I enabled.
So, if you look in expense agent setup,
I can move
to show you
projects.
And now you can see here project
tracking.
So, first you need to enable project
tracking, so this field will be visible
in a web app. A second one, project
visibility, which one you want to use.
As I said, assign projects or all
projects. So, I decide to use all
projects.
And then
now I'm in a web app. I already have
created uh expense, one expense based on
my receipt. I didn't want to upload uh
in a live because we don't want to uh
wait uh until uh receipt is processed.
So, I already have created. We can just
review.
So, this is how you will get when you
upload receipt. Receipt is created. I
have merchant, I have receipt number,
amount, all details, even description,
hotel bank you want purchase, pay by
card,
categorization, hotels, but I have
projects is empty.
So,
now I want to edit, I want to assign
project.
If I click to edit, then I can select
projects and you will see I have only
one project selected.
So, why is that? Because I'm assigned
only to one project. So, I can choose
this one and I will show you in
uh Business Central what I did. End of
project task, I have all project task
enabled. By all project task, I mean
you can see only project task for
posting, not beginning and end
of totals. So, only
uh task for posting. And uh by projects,
even you assign, you can see only active
projects. So, only active projects and
only uh project tasks where you
uh enabled to post. So, I will choose
for example delivering.
And what I need to do is to click save.
And all good, I have created and I have
added project
>> [snorts]
>> to this expense.
Now, I can move to Business Central.
And I will show you first this expense
report.
>> [snorts]
>> So, I have this one expense report.
So, you can see all these details here.
In a show billable information,
you can find project I assign and
project task. So, everything is here.
I will not post, I will just make a look
in a preview posting.
So, you can see that I have project
ledger entry
here. So, everything is added
automatically. So, this is what you will
get when you post. But, let's go back
and let's check a project.
I have projects. And if you look this
one,
you will see that assign resources, I
added myself here.
I didn't add two lines and this is the
reason why I can see all
tasks.
But in a case that you want to select,
this is where you need to go assign
resources.
So this is now empty, but that means you
you are not selected only for one
because system will inherit your setup
from project card.
If I look into another one, why we do
not see
other projects, you will see that in the
next project I am not assigned, but if I
add myself now here
and if I go back to expense agent, I
will see this additional project as well
in the list.
So this is everything about enablement
projects in a web app and how to assign
because previously we didn't have the
the best assign a model. So now you have
dedicated resources assigned to
projects. This is up to you how you want
to assign or to use all projects.
Thank you for watching this video.
>> [music]